<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>CSC 451 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>HCI </h3>
    <p>It is the study of how people interact with computers and to what extent computers are not yet developed for successful interaction with humans.<br/>

HCI consists of 3 main parts – Users, computer and interaction
</p><br/>
<h3>Interactive Design  </h3>
    <p>Most of our everyday ¬¬products are interactive products.<br/>
Our cell phones, smart Tv, alarm clock, watch, radio, gaming console, laptop, fitness tracker. etc. <br/>
Most of these devices are easy to use <br/>
But some other devices aren’t so easy to use. Why?<br/> <br/>
This is because some devices are designed primarily with the user in mind. They are easy to use and enjoy.
</p><br/>
    <p>Some other devices weren’t made with the users in mind, example is a stove that requires a combination of button presses that are not obvious as to which ones to press together or separately.
These devices will need to be learned to be used.
Some devices can be frustrating to use.
</p><br/>
    <p>Alan Cooper (in 2018), a well-known UX guru says that software still suffers from the same interaction errors that were around 20 years ago even though interaction design has been inexistence for more than 25 years. He believes that the reason for this is because many apps don’t follow even the most basic UX principles such as undo option.</p><br/>
    <p>To rectify these issues, we need to be able to reduce the negative aspects (the frustrations and annoyance) of the user experience while enhancing the positive ones (enjoyment and efficacy). This entails developing interactive products that are easy, efficient and pleasurable to the user’s perspective.</p><br/>
<h3>Good And Poor Designs</h3>

    <p>The concern of interactive design is to develop interactive products that are usable. By usable we mean products that are easy to learn, effective to use and provide enjoyable user experience. 
A good way to think about interactive designs is to compare a well-designed and poorly designed one.
</p><br/>
<h3>What is Interaction Design</h3>
    <p>Designing interactive products to support the way people communicate and interact in their everyday and working lives. 
It is about creating a user experience that augments and enhance the way people work, communicate and interact.
</p><br/>
    <p>Usability and User Experience Goals <br/>
Part of the process of understanding users is to be clear about the primary objectives of developing an interactive product for them.
Usability goals is concerned with meeting specific usability criteria, such as efficiency.
User Experience is concerned with the explicit nature of the user’s experience.

How a product feels and looks is linked with usability of the product but it is a user experience. How the user experience comes is down to the usability of the product.
</p><br/>


    </div>