<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>PHY 103 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>Heat, work and energy, temperature </h3>
    <p>Heat is a form of energy that is transferred from one body to another as a result of a difference in temperature. Heat is measured in units of energy, such as joules or calories, and is often used to describe the amount of thermal energy that is being transferred between two objects.</p><br/>
    <p>Work is the energy that is transferred from one body to another as a result of a force being applied over a distance. Work is also measured in units of energy, such as joules, and is a measure of the amount of force applied to an object.</p><br/>
    <p>Temperature is a measure of the average kinetic energy of the particles in a substance. It is typically measured in degrees Celsius (°C) or degrees Fahrenheit (°F), and is a measure of how hot or cold an object is. The higher the temperature of a substance, the more energy its particles have, and the faster they are moving.</p><br/>
    <p>Heat, work, and energy are all related because they are all forms of energy that can be transferred between objects. When heat is transferred from one object to another, it can cause the temperature of the objects to change, and this can lead to changes in the energy and work that the objects can do. Similarly, when work is done on an object, it can cause changes in the object's energy and temperature.</p><br/>
    <p>Understanding these concepts is important for many fields, including engineering, physics, and chemistry, as they are fundamental to understanding how energy is transferred and how it can be harnessed or controlled. They are also important for understanding the behavior of materials and how they respond to changes in temperature and energy.</p><br/>
    <h3>Specific heat of solids, liquids and gases</h3>

    
    <p>The specific heat of a substance is a measure of the amount of heat required to raise the temperature of a given mass of the substance by a certain degree. It is typically expressed in units of joules per gram per degree Celsius (J/g°C).</p><br/>
    <p>The specific heat of solids is generally higher than that of liquids and gases, due to the stronger intermolecular forces and tighter packing of atoms in solids. Solids also have lower thermal conductivity than liquids and gases, which means that they are more resistant to heat transfer.</p><br/>
    <p>The specific heat of liquids is generally lower than that of solids, but higher than that of gases. This is due to the fact that liquids have weaker intermolecular forces and more freedom of movement than solids, but are still more densely packed than gases.</p><br/>
    <p>The specific heat of gases is generally the lowest of the three states of matter, due to the large distance between gas molecules and their low density. Gases also have the highest thermal conductivity of the three states of matter, which means that they are the most readily able to transfer heat.</p><br/>



    </div>