<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>CSC 437 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>Artificial Intelligence</h3>
    <p>Two big questions by philosophers</p><br/>
    <p>1. How does the human mind work?</p><br/>
    <p>2. Can non-humans have minds?</p><br/>
    <p>Some philosophers believe that machine can do everything humans can do.</p><br/>
    <p>Others have openly opposed this idea. Claiming that such highly sophisticated behaviours such as love, creative discovery and moral choice will always be beyond the scope of any machine.</p><br/>
    <p>Intelligent: Ability to understand and learn things.</p><br/>
    <p>Ability to think and understand instead of doing things by instinct or automation.</p><br/>
    <h3>What is Human intelligence?</h3>

    <p>1. Thinking</p><br/>
	<p>2. Learning and Understanding</p><br/>
    <p>3. Knowledge applying</p><br/>
    <p>4. Acting (Knowing how to behave in a different environment)</p><br/>
    <p>5. Perceiving (the environment)</p><br/>
    <p>6. Automated Behaviour***</p><br/>
    <p>7. Solving Problem (and making decisions)</p><br/>
    <p>8. Pattern Matching and recognition</p><br/>
    <h3>Intelligent System is Ability of a system to</h3>

    <p>Intelligent System is Ability of a system to</p><br/>
	<p>- Calculate</p><br/>
    <p>- Reason</p><br/>
	<p>- Learn from experience</p><br/>
    <p>- Solve problems and comprehend complex ideas</p><br/>
	<p>- Store and retrieve information from memory</p><br/>
    <p>- Use natural language fluently</p><br/>
	<p>- Perceive relationships and analogies</p><br/>
    <p>- Classify, generalize and adapt to new situations.</p><br/>
    <h3>Artificial Intelligence</h3>

	<p>It means making computer that thinks. Automation of activities we associate with human thinking. It means making computer that thinks. These activities are Decision making, pattern recognition, learning patterns. <br/> Creating machines that perform function that require intelligence when performed by people. <br/><br/></p><br/>
    <p>Creating machines that perform function that require intelligence when performed by people <br/>***Telling a machine to do something that requires intelligence***</p><br/>
	<p>Artificial: Something produced by human effort or art rather than originating naturally.</p><br/>
    <p>Intelligence: The ability to acquire knowledge and use it.</p><br/>
<p>o, what is AI? <br/>
	The study of ideas that enable computers to the intelligent.</p><br/>
    <p>So, what is AI?</p><br/>
    <p>The study of ideas that enable computers to the intelligent.</p><br/>
    <p>Strong AI vs Weak AI</p><br/>
    <p>Strong AI: A robot that is autonomous, thinks for itself and makes its own decisions. Can learn and adapt to new situations and can communicate with humans through the use of language.</p><br/>
    <p>Weak AI: It’s used to build a computer program that simulates a particular intelligent activity.
	Ex. Playing chess.</p><br/>
    <p>Categories of AI</p><br/>
    <p>o Systems that act like humans 	- Behaviour	- Humans<br/>
o Systems that act rationally 		- Behaviour	- Rational<br/>
o Systems that think like humans	- Thought	-Humans<br/>
o Systems that think rationally	- Thought	- Rational</p><br/>

    </div>
	

	