<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>CSC 428 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>COMPUTER GRAPHICS</h3>
    <p>Computer graphics are the visual representations of data and images that are created, edited, and displayed on a computer screen. These graphics can be static or animated, and are used in a wide variety of applications including video games, movies, television, advertising, websites, and scientific visualization.</p><br/>
    <p>The field of computer graphics has a long history, with the first computer graphics being created in the 1950s using simple line drawings and basic shapes. Over the years, the technology has advanced significantly, and today we have sophisticated software programs and hardware devices that can create highly realistic and complex graphics.</p><br/>
    <p>One of the key technologies used in computer graphics is 3D modeling, which involves creating a virtual 3D representation of an object or environment. This is done using specialized software such as Autodesk Maya or Blender, which allow users to manipulate the shape, size, and appearance of the model. 3D modeling is used in a wide range of applications, including video games, movies, and product design.</p><br/>
    <p>Another important aspect of computer graphics is rendering, which is the process of converting a 3D model into a 2D image or animation. This can be done using various techniques such as ray tracing, which involves simulating the way light interacts with objects in the virtual environment. Rendering can be a computationally intensive process, and specialized hardware such as graphics processing units (GPUs) are often used to speed it up.</p><br/>
    <p>Computer graphics are also used in scientific visualization, which involves creating visual representations of data in order to better understand and analyze it. This can be used in fields such as medicine, meteorology, and engineering, and can help to identify patterns and trends that may not be immediately apparent in raw data.</p><br/>
    <p>One of the most well-known applications of computer graphics is in the entertainment industry, where they are used to create stunning visual effects in movies and video games. Many of the most iconic movie moments of the past few decades have been created using computer graphics, such as the Jurassic Park dinosaurs and the Star Wars lightsaber battles.</p><br/>
    <p>Computer graphics also have the ability to be highly efficient and cost-effective. In many cases, it is much cheaper and faster to create a computer-generated image or animation than it would be to build or film the same thing in the real world.</p><br/>
    <p>However, there are also some limitations to computer graphics. While they can create highly realistic images, they are still limited by the algorithms and algorithms and hardware used to create them. Additionally, some people may argue that computer graphics lack the same level of emotion and depth as real-life images and videos.</p><br/>
    <p>Overall, computer graphics have become an integral part of our daily lives, and are used in a wide range of applications from entertainment to scientific research. As technology continues to advance, it is likely that we will see even more impressive and realistic computer graphics in the future.</p><br/>
    </div>