<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>CSC 420 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>COMPUTER SECURITY</h3>
    <p>Computer security is an essential aspect of modern technology that protects computer systems and networks from unauthorized access or attacks. The term computer security encompasses various measures, including hardware, software, and other strategies that protect against cyber threats. In the digital age, computers and the internet have become integral parts of our daily lives, and as such, we rely on them for a wide range of activities, including communication, banking, and entertainment. Therefore, the security of these systems is of utmost importance to ensure that our personal information and data remain safe and secure.</p><br/>
    <p>There are several types of threats that computer security aims to protect against, including viruses, worms, Trojan horses, and malware. These threats can infect a computer system and spread to other computers on the network, causing damage or stealing data. Hackers can also exploit vulnerabilities in computer systems to gain access to sensitive information or disrupt operations. To protect against these threats, computer security systems use various measures, including firewalls, antivirus software, and encryption.</p><br/>
    <p>Firewalls are a crucial component of computer security as they act as a barrier between a computer and the internet. Firewalls monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules. They can block unauthorized access and prevent potentially malicious traffic from entering the system.</p><br/>
    <p>Antivirus software is another essential tool that helps protect against malware and viruses. Antivirus software scans files and programs for potential threats and blocks or removes them if they are detected. It is essential to keep antivirus software up to date to ensure that it can detect the latest threats.</p><br/>
    <p>Encryption is another key aspect of computer security that helps protect data from unauthorized access. Encryption involves converting data into a code that can only be accessed by someone with the proper decryption key. This ensures that only authorized individuals can access sensitive information, such as financial records or personal data.</p><br/>
    <p>In addition to these measures, computer security also involves implementing strong passwords and regularly updating them. Passwords should be unique and difficult to guess, and it is recommended to use different passwords for different accounts. Updating passwords regularly can help prevent unauthorized access in the event that a password is compromised.</p><br/>
    <p>Another aspect of computer security is the physical security of computer systems. This involves protecting hardware from damage, theft, or tampering. Physical security measures can include locking computer cabinets, installing security cameras, and using biometric authentication methods.</p><br/>
    <p>Computer security also involves training employees on cyber threats and best practices for protecting against them. This can include educating employees on how to recognize phishing scams, avoiding suspicious emails and links, and following secure password practices.</p><br/>
    <p>Computer security is a vital aspect of modern technology that protects computer systems and networks from unauthorized access and attacks. It involves a range of measures, including firewalls, antivirus software, encryption, and physical security. Implementing these measures and educating employees on best practices can help ensure the safety and security of computer systems and the data they contain.</p><br/>
    </div>