<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>GNS 201 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>LAGOS AND IT'S ENVIRONMENTS</h3>
    <p>Lagos is the largest city in Nigeria and is located on the western coast of the country. It is a bustling metropolis that is home to over 20 million people, making it one of the most populous cities in Africa. Lagos is known for its vibrant culture, bustling markets, and vibrant nightlife, and it is a hub of commerce and trade for the entire country.</p><br/>
    <p>The city is divided into several distinct areas, each with its own unique character and atmosphere. The Lagos Island is the oldest part of the city and is home to many of the city's landmarks, such as the Lagos State House, the Lagos Central Mosque, and the Lagos Cathedral. The Island is also home to many of the city's most luxurious hotels, restaurants, and shopping centers.</p><br/>
    <p>The Victoria Island area is known for its high-end residential neighborhoods and upscale shopping centers. The Ikoyi neighborhood is home to many of the city's wealthy residents and is known for its tree-lined streets, parks, and well-manicured lawns.</p><br/>
    <p>The Mainland area of Lagos is home to many of the city's working-class neighborhoods, as well as its industrial and commercial areas. The Lagos Mainland is known for its bustling markets, crowded streets, and vibrant nightlife. It is also home to the University of Lagos, one of the top universities in the country.</p><br/>
    <p>The environment in Lagos is diverse, with many different ecosystems and habitats within the city limits. The Lagos Lagoon is a large body of water that runs through the city and is home to a wide variety of fish and other marine life. The Lagos Lagoon also serves as an important transportation route for the city, with boats and ferries carrying people and goods between the different parts of the city.</p><br/>
    <p>The city is also home to several nature reserves, including the Lekki Conservation Centre, which is home to many species of wildlife, including monkeys, crocodiles, and birds. The conservation center is a popular tourist attraction and is a great place to learn about the local flora and fauna.</p><br/>
    <p>Despite its many attractions, Lagos is not without its challenges. The city is known for its high levels of pollution, which is caused by the large number of cars and buses on the roads and the industrial activity in the city. The pollution has had a negative impact on the air quality and the health of the city's residents.</p><br/>
    <p>Lagos is also prone to flooding, due to its location on the coast and its low-lying areas. The city has suffered from severe flooding in the past, which has caused widespread damage and disrupted the daily lives of its residents.</p><br/>
    <p>Despite these challenges, Lagos remains a vibrant and dynamic city that is full of life and energy. It is a city that is constantly evolving and changing, and it is a great place to visit and experience the rich culture and history of Nigeria.</p><br/>



    </div>