<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>CSC 214 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h2>Database management system (DBMS)</h2>
    <p>A database management system (DBMS) is a software program that allows users to create, update, and manage a database. It provides a structured environment for storing, organizing, and accessing data in a systematic way. The DBMS enables users to create tables, fields, and relationships between different pieces of data, and provides tools for searching, sorting, and retrieving data as needed. It also provides security measures to protect data from unauthorized access or modification. Overall, a DBMS plays a crucial role in enabling organizations to efficiently manage and use their data resources.</p>
    <p>A database management system (DBMS) is a software tool that allows for the creation, organization, and management of a database. It is essential for storing, organizing, and accessing data in a structured manner.</p>
    <p>There are several types of DBMS, including relational, object-oriented, and NoSQL databases. Relational databases are based on tables and rows, with data organized into columns. Object-oriented databases store data in the form of objects, which are defined by their attributes and behaviors. NoSQL databases, on the other hand, are designed for handling large amounts of data and are well-suited for handling unstructured data.</p>
    <p>The DBMS is responsible for the overall management of the database, including data input, data manipulation, data retrieval, and data security. It also plays a crucial role in the database design process, ensuring that the database is optimized for efficiency and scalability.</p>
    <p>One of the primary advantages of using a DBMS is that it allows users to access and manipulate data in a centralized and organized manner. This makes it easier to perform tasks such as data analysis, reporting, and decision-making. It also allows for data integrity and consistency, as the DBMS ensures that data is stored and accessed in a consistent manner.</p>
    <p>In conclusion, a database management system is a crucial tool for managing and accessing data in a structured manner. It allows for efficient data manipulation, organization, and retrieval, making it an essential tool for businesses and organizations of all sizes.</p>


<h1>Note 2</h1>
<p>A database is a collection of related data that has an implicit meaning and represents some aspect of the real world. It is designed, built, and populated with data for a specific purpose and has an intended group of users and some preconvinced applications in which these users are interested. Databases play a critical role in almost all areas where computers are used including business, engineering, medicine, law, education, and library science. </p>
<p>A database can be of any size and varying complexity, it may contain a few hundred records or millions. This huge amount of information must be organized and managed so that users can search for retrieve and update the data as needed.</p>
<p>A database management system (DBMS) is a collection of programs that enables users to create and maintain a database. It provides an environment that is both convenient and efficient to use and interfaces with application programs so that the data contained in the database can be used by multiple applications and users. The DBMS exerts centralized control of the database, prevents unauthorized users from accessing the data, and ensures privacy of data. The objective of the DBMS is to provide a convenient and effective method of defining, storing and retrieving the information contained in the database.</p>
<p>The DBMS allows users to access and manipulate the data contained in the database in a convenient and effective manner. It is a general-purpose software system that facilitates the process of Defining, Constructing, and Manipulating databases for various applications.</p>
<p>Databases are used in various industries such as banking, airlines, universities, sales, manufacturing, and human resources. In banking, all transactions are recorded in a database, in airlines, reservations and schedules are recorded, in universities, registration and grades are recorded, in sales, customers, products, and purchases are recorded and in manufacturing, production, inventory, orders, and supply chain are recorded. Human resources use databases to record employee records, salaries, and tax deductions.</p>
<p>In summary, a database is a collection of related data that has an implicit meaning and represents some aspect of the real world. It is designed, built, and populated with data for a specific purpose and has an intended group of users and some preconvinced applications in which these users are interested. A database management system (DBMS) is a collection of programs that enables users to create and maintain a database.</p>
<p>It provides an environment that is both convenient and efficient to use and interfaces with application programs so that the data contained in the database can be used by multiple applications and users. The DBMS exerts centralized control of the database, prevents unauthorized users from accessing the data, and ensures privacy of data. The objective of the DBMS is to provide a convenient and effective method of defining, storing and retrieving the information contained in the database. Databases are used in various industries to record and manage important information for effective decision making.</p>

    </div>