<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>PHY 101 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>Newton's law of motion</h3>
    <p>Newton's laws of motion are a set of three laws that describe the relationship between a body and the forces acting upon it, as well as the relationship between the body and the motion it undergoes. These laws were first described by English physicist and mathematician Sir Isaac Newton in the late 17th century and form the foundation of classical mechanics.</p><br/>
    <p>The first law, also known as the law of inertia, states that a body will remain at rest or in motion at a constant velocity unless acted upon by an external force. This means that if a body is not being pushed or pulled, it will continue moving in a straight line at a constant speed, and if it is at rest, it will remain at rest unless a force is applied to it.</p><br/>
    <p>The second law states that the force applied to a body is equal to the mass of the body multiplied by its acceleration. This is often expressed as the equation F = ma, where F is the force applied to the body, m is the mass of the body, and a is the acceleration of the body.</p><br/>
    <p>The third law states that for every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction. This means that when one body exerts a force on another body, the second body will also exert an equal and opposite force back on the first body. This is known as the principle of action and reaction.</p><br/>
    <p>These laws are fundamental to the understanding of how objects move and behave, and they are used in the study of mechanics, engineering, and many other fields.</p><br/>
    <h3>Surface tension and capillarity effect</h3>
    <p>Surface tension is a property of a liquid that allows it to resist an external force and maintain its shape. It is caused by the cohesive forces between the molecules of the liquid, which are stronger at the surface of the liquid than within the bulk of the liquid. This results in the surface of the liquid behaving as if it were a thin, flexible membrane.</p><br/>
    <p>Capillarity is the ability of a liquid to flow through small spaces, such as the narrow tubes of a capillary. This is due to the combination of surface tension and adhesive forces between the liquid and the surface it is in contact with. When a liquid is placed in a capillary, the cohesive forces between the molecules of the liquid pull the surface of the liquid upward, creating a meniscus. This phenomenon is commonly seen in drinking straws and in the roots of plants, where it helps to transport water from the soil to the leaves.
</p><br/>

    </div>