<div class="none">
    <br/><br/><br/><br/>
    <center><h2>ENT 302 Short Note</h2></center>
    <h3>Water purification</h3>
    <p>Water purification is the process of removing impurities, contaminants, and bacteria from water to make it safe for drinking, bathing, and other household uses. While the Earth's water supply is constantly being replenished through the water cycle, it is not always safe for consumption due to pollution, natural contaminants, and other factors. Therefore, it is important to have a system in place to purify water before it is used.</p><br/>
    <p>There are several methods of water purification, including physical, chemical, and biological methods. Physical methods involve filtering water through a physical barrier such as a filter or a membrane. These methods can remove larger particles such as dirt, sediment, and algae, but are not effective at removing bacteria or viruses.</p><br/>
    <p>Chemical methods involve using chemicals to kill or remove contaminants from water. One common method is chlorination, which involves adding chlorine to water to kill bacteria and viruses. Other chemical methods include the use of ozone, ultraviolet light, and hydrogen peroxide. These methods can be effective at removing bacteria and viruses, but they may also leave behind chemical residues that can be harmful if consumed.</p><br/>
    <p>Biological methods involve using living organisms or enzymes to purify water. One example is the use of bacteria to break down organic matter and remove contaminants. Another example is the use of enzymes to break down proteins and other contaminants. These methods can be effective at removing contaminants, but they may also require a longer treatment time and may not be suitable for all types of water.</p><br/>
    <p>In addition to these methods, there are also several technologies that are used to purify water. One example is reverse osmosis, which involves forcing water through a membrane to remove contaminants. Another example is distillation, which involves boiling water and collecting the steam, which is then cooled and condensed back into pure water.</p><br/>
    <p>Water purification is an important process for ensuring that people have access to clean and safe drinking water. It is also important for industries such as pharmaceuticals, food processing, and power generation, which require large amounts of purified water for their operations.</p><br/>
    <p>However, water purification can also be a complex and expensive process. It requires the use of specialized equipment, chemicals, and trained personnel. In addition, it generates a large amount of waste, which must be properly disposed of to prevent environmental contamination.</p><br/>
    <p>One of the main challenges of water purification is the presence of emerging contaminants, which are chemicals that are not regulated by traditional water treatment methods. These contaminants, which include pharmaceuticals, personal care products, and other chemicals, can have harmful effects on human health and the environment.</p><br/>


    </div>